Guide to the Red Falcons of America Records TAM.337
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Red Falcons of America Records
1932-1938
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Red Falcons of America.
TAM.337
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
The Red Falcons of America was a socialist organization for children between the ages of eight and fifteen, established ca. 1932, and affiliated with the Socialist Party (U.S.). The collection contains circulars, constitutions, correspondence, flyers, manuals, minutes, newsletters, programs and reports. The bulk of the material is concerned with the Red Falcons' founding, organization, political program, educational activities, plans to establish a summer camp, and relations with the Socialist Party and the Young People's Socialist League, in particular during the period of factional dispute leading up to the 1936 split within the Socialist Party.
Box 1
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number associated with this collection is 1950.050.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically.
The files are grouped into one series:
Missing Title
I, Subject Files
Historical/Biographical Note
The Red Falcons of America was a socialist organization for children between the ages of 8 and 15, established ca. 1932, and affiliated with the Socialist Party (U.S.).
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains circulars, constitutions, correspondence, flyers, manuals, minutes, newsletters, programs and reports. The bulk of the material is concerned with the Red Falcons' founding, organization, political program, educational activities, plans to establish a summer camp, and relations with the Socialist Party and the Young People's Socialist League, in particular during the period of factional dispute leading up to the 1936 split with the Socialist Party. Notable correspondents include Edna Peters Keller (Red Falcon national chairperson) and SP leaders William E. Bohn and Clarence Senior.
Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence.; Children |x Political activity |z United States.; Socialism and youth -- United States.; Reports.; Newsletters.; Socialist Party (U.S.); Young People's Socialist League; Keller, Edna Peters; Bohn, William E.; Senior, Clarence Ollson, 1903-1974
- Series I: General Files
  - Red Falcons of America, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Red Falcons of America, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Red Falcons of America, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Red Falcons of America, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Red Falcons of America, Jan 1935-Feb 1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Red Falcons of America, Mar 1935-Jul 1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Red Falcons of America, Aug 1935-Sep 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Red Falcons of America, Oct 1935-Dec 1935 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Red Falcons of America, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Red Falcons of America, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)